rusu.co.uk 2010-05-16

# Privacy Policy

### Privacy Policy

Reading University Students' Union is committed to protecting the rights and privacy of individuals in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998 (DPA). This privacy statement is here to help you understand what we do with your personal data in relation to our website, www.rusu.co.uk. The use of [www.rusu.co.uk](http://www.rusu.co.uk/) implies your agreement and acceptance of the clauses of our Privacy Policy. If you do not agree or accept this policy then we request you do not to provide us with any personal information. We will process your personal data according to the principles set out in the DPA and will keep it on a secure server. 

**Registering on our website**

When you register on [www.rusu.co.uk](http://www.rusu.co.uk/) RUSU, or a data processor operating on behalf of RUSU, will collect personal data from you such as:

  * Name and contact details for instance, your e-mail address and telephone number; 
  * HTTP protocol elements such as, the server address, the IP address and browser details; 
  * Click-stream data (the type of computer and browsing software you use, and originating website etc.; 
  * Demographic data such as, country and telephone area code where your computer is located; 
  * Preference data: search items of our website, any advertisements you clicked on.. 

We may monitor your usage of this website. This may include monitoring (how many times you visit, which pages you go to, traffic data, location data and the originating domain name of a user's internet service provider). This information helps us to build a profile of our users. Some of this data will be aggregated or statistical, which means that we will not be able to identify you individually. Please see further the section on ' **Use of cookies** ' below.

**Use of cookies**

When you use this website, we may collect information about your computer, such as your IP address and/or browser, which we will use for administration purposes and statistical analysis. This information will not usually identify you personally.

We may also obtain information about your online movements and use of the internet. We do this by placing a 'cookie', which is a small file, on your computer's hard disk. Cookies are used for several reasons:

  * to recognise you whenever you visit this website 
  * to speed up access to this website (so you do not have to log on each time) 
  * to store your personal preferences 
  * to build a profile about you 
  * to better target our marketing and advertising campaigns

The vast majority of web browsers accept cookies. However, you can change your browser settings so that cookies are not accepted. If you do this, you may lose some of the functionality of this website.

**Disclosure of your personal data**

We may disclose your personal data to:

  * our agents and service providers (eg providers of web hosting, survey provider or maintenance services) 
  * law enforcement agencies in connection with any investigation to help prevent unlawful activity 
  * our business partners in accordance with the ' **Marketing and opting out** ' section above.

**Marketing and opting out**

Unless you have asked us not to do so, we may contact you by _(eg mail, telephone, SMS, text/picture/video message, fax, email)_ about _(eg products, services, promotions, special offers, charitable causes)_ which may be of interest to you.

_(or)_

We may share your personal data with organisations who are our business partners and we or they may contact you, unless you have asked us or them not to do so, by _(specify, eg mail, telephone, SMS, text/picture/video message, fax, email, other)_ about _(eg products, services, promotions, special offers, charitable causes)_ which may be of interest to you.

If you prefer not to receive any further marketing communications from us, you can opt out at any time. See **"How to Unsubscribe"** below.

**Information about other individuals**

If you give us information on behalf of someone else, you confirm that the other person has appointed you to act on his/her behalf and has agreed that you can:

  * give consent on his/her behalf to the processing of his or her personal data 
  * receive on his/her behalf any data protection notices 
  * give consent to the transfer of his/her personal data abroad 
  * give consent to the processing of his or her _(sensitive personal data)_.

**How to unsubscribe**

If you do give us your details and then decide you do not want us to use your details anymore you can unsubscribe by:

  * clicking on the 'unsubscribe' link in any of the RUSU e-mails you receive. 
  * contacting us directly as detailed below.

**How we use your personal information**

Your personal data will be used for the following purposes:

  * to help us develop the design and layout of our website 

Sometimes this information may also be used by RUSU, RUSU's data processors and our associated Third Parties, such as The University of Reading,to inform you about changes to the website, new services and products or offers and events that you might find interesting. RUSU and Third Parties may contact you for any of the above purposes whether by telephone, email, fax or in writing. 

RUSU reserves the right to access and disclose individually identifiable information to comply with applicable laws and obligations, to operate our systems properly or to protect ourselves or other users. RUSU also reserves the right to disclose individually identifiable information to third parties if a complaint arises concerning your use of RUSU's website.

To ensure strict security procedures covering all aspects of processing your personal data and to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure we may ask for proof of identity before we disclose your personal information to you. 

We welcome your questions and comments about privacy issues. Should you have such comments or have a complaint about how we are using your personal data, please contact Andrew R. Makowsky ([a.makowsky@reading.ac.uk](mailto:a.makowsky@reading.ac.uk)) or by letter.

**Reading University Students' Union  
** FAO: **Andrew R. Makowsky**  
Whiteknights  
Reading  
RG6 6AZ

**Tel:** 0118 378 4100  
 **Fax:** 0118 378 4115

Page Last Modified: 02 Apr 2010
